<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Partner Stories &#8211; Museum of the Citizen</title>
	<atom:link href="./index.html" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>./../../../index.html</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 30 Aug 2017 12:37:09 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-GB</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.9</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Herbert Museum and Art Gallery</title>
		<link>./../../../herbert-museum-and-art-gallery/index.html</link>
		<pubDate>Thu, 21 Jan 2016 11:07:02 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[bm-editor]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Partner Stories]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=767</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[&#8216;When I look back over the last decade at the Herbert Museum’s programme I am]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<blockquote><p>&#8216;When I look back over the last decade at the Herbert Museum’s programme I am astounded at just how much support we have received from the British Museum to create engaging exhibitions.&#8217;</p>
<p>– Chris Kirby</p></blockquote>
<p><img class="wp-image-771 size-medium" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/RomanEmpire_142-2000x1135.jpg" alt="RomanEmpire_142" width="2000" height="1135" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/RomanEmpire_142-2000x1135.jpg 2000w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/RomanEmpire_142-300x170.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 2000px) 100vw, 2000px" /></p>
<p>The loans and touring exhibitions provided by the British Museum has created some catalyst for development, and in doing so a lasting legacy for our organisation. Through the British Museum partnership we have developed audiences, partnerships and staff expertise. We look forward to what this partnership can achieve going forward.</p>
<p><strong>Throne of Weapons, 2005<br />
</strong>Our productive relationship with the British Museum started in 2005 when we hosted the Throne of Weapons &#8211; a powerful contemporary art piece by Mozambique artist Kester. During its time in Coventry, the Throne was taken for a special service in Coventry Cathedral.</p>
<p><strong><em>La Bouche Du Roi</em> and <em>China, Journey to the East</em>, 2009<br />
</strong>In 2009, the Herbert exhibited two concurrent British Museum exhibitions: <em><a href="http://www.artfund.org/supporting-museums/art-weve-helped-buy/artwork/9798/la-bouche-du-roi" target="_blank">La Bouche Du Roi</a></em> was a large contemporary installation by Benin artist <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Romuald_Hazoum%C3%A8" target="_blank">Romuald Hazoumé</a> exploring the slave trade. The second was <em>China, Journey to East</em> which helped create a partnership with our neighbour Compton Verney and their important oriental collection; we also developed a close link with Coventry University’s Chinese student community.</p>
<figure id="attachment_768" style="max-width: 804px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img class="size-full wp-image-768" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/18romuald-5.jpg" alt="La Bouche du Roi by Romuald Hazoumé" width="804" height="293" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/18romuald-5.jpg 804w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/18romuald-5-300x109.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 804px) 100vw, 804px" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">La Bouche du Roi by Romuald Hazoumé</figcaption></figure>
<p><strong><em>Secret Egypt</em>, 2011<br />
</strong>The British Museum lent some key objects to <em>Secret Egypt: Unravelling Truth from Myth</em>, a Herbert exhibition which became the first venue of a national tour. At the time this was the most successful exhibition in the Herbert’s fifty year history.</p>
<p><strong>Sikh Fortress Turban, 2013<br />
</strong>The Sikh Fortress Turban spotlight exhibition provided a wonderful opportunity to engage with Coventry’s important Sikh community. Interestingly, during the exhibition, a local incident had raised an issue of trust between the community and the Local Authority. The turban display was used as a public meeting place for Local Council officials and members of the Sikh community to show a united friendship.</p>
<p><strong><em>Roman Empire: Power &amp; People</em>, 2014<br />
</strong>This touring exhibition provided a catalyst to present alongside <em>Roman Empire: Power &amp; People </em>the first ever exhibition about the Roman occupation of the local region, drawing together loans from Leicester, Warwickshire, Nuneaton, Rugby and the <a href="http://www.luntromanfort.org/" target="_blank">Lunt Roman Fort</a>. The exhibition helped to channel a significant number of people to the Lunt Roman Fort during the summer.</p>
<p><strong>The Future?<br />
</strong>Going forward we would love to work with the British Museum on developing co-curation projects around select items in its collection that might resonate with the local community and through this project work with a number of targeted groups in Coventry to explore their creativity and learning.</p>
<p><strong>Chris Kirby, Director of Collections, <a href="http://www.culturecoventry.com/" target="_blank">Culture Coventry</a></strong></p>
<p><strong> </strong></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A new South Asia Gallery for Manchester Museum</title>
		<link>./../../../manchester-museum/index.html</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2015 06:15:01 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[bm-editor]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Partner Stories]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=379</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[&#8220;2017 is the 70th anniversary of Partition and there&#8217;s a UK/India Year of Culture. Having]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<blockquote><p><strong>&#8220;2017 is the 70th anniversary of Partition and there&#8217;s a UK/India Year of Culture. Having the South Asia Gallery well underway, although clearly not open, is going to be an important milestone.&#8221;</strong> – Nick Merriman</p></blockquote>
<p><img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-384" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/csfl8984_10577025466_o-2000x1333.jpg" alt="csfl8984_10577025466_o" width="2000" height="1333" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/csfl8984_10577025466_o-2000x1333.jpg 2000w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/csfl8984_10577025466_o-300x200.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 2000px) 100vw, 2000px" /></p>
<p><b>The history of Manchester Museum<br />
</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">I&#8217;ve been Director of Manchester Museum for nearly 10 years. When I started, the Museum had recently finished a major capital investment, which gave it expanded facilities, bringing the building into the 20th century, if not the 21st.</span></p>
<p>But it didn&#8217;t update or address most of its permanent galleries, so my job has been to raise funds for a rolling programme of gallery renewals, approximately one a year. We&#8217;ve now come to the end of that cycle, and all the galleries that were about 25 or 30 years old have been updated and modernised. Over the same period, visitor numbers have more than doubled. There was an original target of getting up to 200,000 visitors a year to come to the Museum when the developments were all complete. We&#8217;re now at nearly 450,000 so we get very congested at times!</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Our temporary exhibition space is only 184m</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">2</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">, which means we can&#8217;t participate in most large-scale national and international touring programmes. The obvious next step for us is to expand our facilities so that we can meet the needs of larger audiences and extend those audiences to some of the areas that we don&#8217;t cover. In particular, we don&#8217;t get quite get enough adult visitors – we&#8217;re seen as a family museum. Niche groups, such as people of South Asian descent comprise 11% of the city of Manchester population and 9% of Greater Manchester, but only 2% of museum visitors.</span></p>
<p>The opportunity to do the South Asia Gallery can help us address that. I think that one of the reasons we get a relatively low turnout is that South Asian cultures are not very strongly represented in the Museum.</p>
<blockquote><p><strong>&#8220;It&#8217;s an important two-way relationship for our staff and British Museum staff to have the opportunity to work together.&#8221;</strong></p></blockquote>
<p><b>Our partnership with the British Museum<br />
</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">We&#8217;ve had a partnership with the British Museum for a very long time – we&#8217;re one of the oldest regional partners, so it was quite easy for us to move on to the next stage, which was to think about a partnership gallery when the opportunity arose.</span></p>
<p>The University and the City of Manchester&#8217;s relations with modern India are extremely important. Also, as our largest South Asian populations are from Pakistan and Bangladesh, there&#8217;s a large percentage coming from those countries to visit friends and relations in local communities. In some ways, it was an ideal opportunity to bring together a whole series of issues and to be able to draw on the British Museum&#8217;s collection, where our own is relatively weak. It&#8217;s a fantastic opportunity.</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Of course, there are all sorts of benefits to working in partnership. One is the British Museum playing a truly national role in bringing its objects to Manchester. It&#8217;s an important two-way relationship for our staff and British Museum staff to have the opportunity to work together. As a university museum outside of London, we&#8217;re able to be a little more experimental and act as a laboratory for museum practice.</span></p>
<p>We have a tiny curatorial staff compared to the British Museum, so being able to work with colleagues in the learning and curatorial departments means that we can gain greatly in terms of skills. The partnership with the British Museum also helps us with fundraising, because the British Museum brand is such a leading one. I&#8217;m certainly very optimistic in terms of that helping the South Asia Gallery and the overall project.</p>
<blockquote><p><strong>&#8220;We&#8217;ve got quite a nice story already, which makes links between the British presence in India, as it was then, and the South Asian diaspora in Manchester&#8230;&#8221;</strong></p></blockquote>
<p><b>Plans for the new South Asia Gallery<br />
</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">The South Asia Gallery is just one component of our overall capital redevelopment, which will also include a new entrance and a 500m<sup>2</sup> temporary exhibition space.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The team has just done an initial concept design, with options for where the South Asia Gallery will be. We&#8217;ve had some very fruitful meetings with British Museum colleagues – from the Asia Department, but also from the Middle East Department, Prints and Drawings and so on – to work with our curators on a storyline. They have provided examples of objects that could be made available, whether that&#8217;s Mughal art, coins or Buddhist statues. We&#8217;ve got quite a nice story already, which makes links between the British presence in India, as it was then, and the South Asian diaspora in Manchester </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">–</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> particularly post-Partition </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">–</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> from the 1950s onwards.</span></p>
<p>2017 is the 70th anniversary of Partition and there&#8217;s a UK/India Year of Culture. Having the South Asia Gallery well underway, although clearly not open, is going to be an important milestone.</p>
<p><b>Engaging the public<br />
</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">The public will be involved in the development of the storylines for the South Asia Gallery and we&#8217;ll work with British Museum colleagues and community representatives to select objects, but a lot of the selection process will come down to pragmatics about what&#8217;s available. We&#8217;ve already started consultation with a range of South Asian community groups and individuals in Manchester, and specialist academics. This week we submit our bid to the Heritage Lottery Fund, where, if we&#8217;re successful, we will really begin work on the detail. Most of the work and the community input will come at that stage.</span></p>
<blockquote><p><strong>&#8220;I&#8217;m looking for a stimulating debate about ideas as well as practicalities.&#8221;</strong></p></blockquote>
<p><b>On Museum of the citizen<br />
</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">I think for us the aim is to raise awareness of the South Asia Gallery, particularly on the back of the successful funding bid. It will be a celebration and a kick-off. There are many more hoops to go through to raise the rest of the money, but we&#8217;ve got a fair wind behind us now. Museum of the citizen will be about the practicalities of the South Asia Gallery </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">–</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> what it will be and what it will do. I&#8217;m particularly interested in discussing some of the issues that we need to address, in terms of the representation of different cultures, how religion is handled, how recent history is handled, how communities will be engaged and have a voice – all of these issues which usually come up around representation, which we&#8217;re familiar with and sensitive to. I&#8217;m looking for a stimulating debate about ideas as well as practicalities.</span></p>
<p><strong>Nick Merriman, Director of Manchester Museum</strong></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Museums and young people at New Walk Museum &#038; Art Gallery, Leicester</title>
		<link>./../../../new-walk-museum-art-gallery-leicester/index.html</link>
		<pubDate>Tue, 24 Nov 2015 11:11:44 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[bm-editor]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Partner Stories]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=362</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[&#8216;Very often people lack a sense of identity and a sense of feeling proud of]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<blockquote><p><strong>&#8216;Very often people lack a sense of identity and a sense of feeling proud of the place where they live. By creating a very strong perception of the city and its long history, we hope that museums will really help to engender an enthusiasm in people for living in the city.&#8217; </strong>&#8211; Sarah Levitt</p></blockquote>
<p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-367" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/New-Walk-Gallery.jpg" alt="New Walk Gallery" width="1204" height="845" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/New-Walk-Gallery.jpg 1204w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/New-Walk-Gallery-300x211.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 1204px) 100vw, 1204px" /></p>
<p><strong>Over 10 years of partnership<br />
</strong>We first started working with the British Museum well over 10 years ago when we were invited to be part of a project called Partnership UK. From that starting point we&#8217;ve had some wonderful activities, spotlight displays and a major exhibition. We have a continuing dialogue about potential loans and projects with the British Museum team, where we discuss what’s appropriate, what&#8217;s available, what Leicester and its communities might like.</p>
<p><strong>The Sikh fortress turban<br />
</strong>We were always really keen on having a display of the Sikh Fortress Turban – a wonderful, huge, dark, tall, blue turban with great steel rings around it. These were used in warfare. It&#8217;s a huge thing and it attracted a deal of interest, both among our Sikh communities and also among the general public. When we get spotlight displays we tend to show them in a small gallery alongside our main galleries. In this case the turban was displayed next to the Victorian art gallery and it was beautifully lit – just that object with some interpretive material. The power of having one stunning individual item is really great &#8211; people came to see the one object. These fortress turbans are really impressive and well known among the Sikh community. They say a huge amount about the Sikh faith. If you go into one of our local Gurdwaras you can see similar rings on display, but not made up as part of a turban. People from all age groups and all backgrounds came to see the turban: young lads, older people, people from the Sikh community, Sikh elders. Everyone was just really fascinated by it.</p>
<p><strong>Indian jade, Babylonian terracotta, and contemporary African art<br />
</strong>We&#8217;ve had something called the<em> Wandering Buddha</em>, which is this most exquisite statue of the Buddha as a tall standing young man – not the normal image that people associate with him. We’ve had the most beautiful Indian jade turtle, a Babylonian terracotta called ‘the Queen of the Night’, plus a wonderful artwork called the ‘Throne of Weapons’, made from decommissioned guns from Mozambique. Within its very diverse communities, Leicester has a large community of refugees and asylum seekers. Lots of young people in Leicester are familiar with that war-torn background, and many have direct family memories of this. The Throne of Weapons came to New Walk Museum for a weekend and we also took it to one of our local colleges. Many of the students had experienced difficulties and they really enjoyed having it there.</p>
<p><strong>Engaging the wider community<br />
</strong>There are several advantages to the British Museum partnership. One of them is that we can bring superb objects here. Also, because people locally know that these are from the British Museum, it&#8217;s an act of generosity, an act of sharing, an act of interest in Leicester&#8217;s communities, because Leicester&#8217;s communities are the British Museum&#8217;s communities. Our partnership is a two-way process – we organised the loan of the reconstructed head of King Richard III to the British Museum and that created a great deal of interest in Leicester. So it raises our profile, it raises the British Museum&#8217;s profile, it shows that investment in the British Museum is something that benefits everybody in the UK, and I think it&#8217;s a very important connection. It encourages people living in Britain to go to the British Museum and to feel that it is <u>their</u> museum.</p>
<p><strong>Museum of the Citizen<br />
</strong>The partnership event with the British Museum on Friday [13 November 2015] was a chance to showcase what&#8217;s important for our young citizens. Leicester is a city of about 330,000 people and we have a very young community – one of the youngest in the whole of the UK. We have lots of students – two universities and a huge college – young families, and we also have a lot of the UK&#8217;s newer communities &#8211; people who have settled in the UK since the last war. We&#8217;re incredibly diverse. Over 20 languages are spoken in Leicester and French is one of the fastest growing languages. We have a wonderful huge Asian community and we recently celebrated Diwali. We have large Muslim, Hindu, Sikh, and Jain communities. We also have growing Chinese, African-Caribbean and Middle-Eastern and Eastern European communities. We also have many refugees and asylum seekers, so it&#8217;s just a great, diverse place to be.</p>
<p><strong>A vision of Leicester for young people<br />
</strong>Leicester is an incredibly diverse city and part of that is the fact that it&#8217;s always been a place that people have come to. People came to Leicester in Medieval times, the 15<sup>th</sup> to 19th centuries, as well as the more recent past. We have long celebrated our association with King Richard III. Finding his remains in Leicester was a fantastic way for museums and heritage to bring people together from every community. This is what museums are about – a feeling of shared heritage, a shared pride and interest in the place where we live and a real sense of pride and confidence. This is something we can do for our young citizens. Very often people lack a sense of identity and a sense of feeling proud of the place where they live. By creating a very strong perception of the city and its long history – Leicester was also a major Roman city – we hope that museums will really help to engender an enthusiasm in people for living in the city. Leicester is a ‘place to be’ these days, and I hope that our museum can help people to feel that.</p>
<p><strong>Sarah Levitt, Head of Arts and Museums at Leicester City Council</strong></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Birmingham Museum &#038; Art Gallery</title>
		<link>./../../../birmingham-museum-art-gallery/index.html</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2015 17:36:39 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[bm-editor]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Partner Stories]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=327</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[&#8220;Having worked in the Staffordshire Hoard galleries for over three years, I have seen first-hand]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<blockquote><p><strong>&#8220;Having worked in the Staffordshire Hoard galleries for over three years, I have seen first-hand how the hoard fascinates people and captures their imagination.&#8221;</strong> &#8211; Anthony Crutch</p></blockquote>
<p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-103" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/Anthony-in-the-gallery-with-the-replica-and-real-anglo-saxon-swords.jpg" alt="Anthony-in-the-gallery-with-the-replica-and-real-anglo-saxon-swords" width="960" height="1600" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/Anthony-in-the-gallery-with-the-replica-and-real-anglo-saxon-swords.jpg 960w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/Anthony-in-the-gallery-with-the-replica-and-real-anglo-saxon-swords-180x300.jpg 180w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /><br />
The first permanent gallery to display the Staffordshire Hoard opened in October 2014. As part of the display, we have included an Anglo-Saxon sword, on loan from the British Museum.</p>
<p>Having worked in the Staffordshire Hoard galleries for over three years, I have seen first-hand how the hoard fascinates people and captures their imagination. They are struck by the intricacy of the detail, the beauty of the designs and the sheer amount of objects.</p>
<p>One thing that makes the hoard so interesting is the fact that the vast majority of it is made up of military equipment, with a large number of decorative pieces of swords. The twisted and fragmentary nature of the objects and the absence of any sword blades in the hoard can make it difficult for people to visualise them in their original context. Having a real Anglo-Saxon sword allows us to show people how these buckled and broken objects would have fitted together – it has become a valuable interpretation tool. This really helps people understand what these objects would have looked like and how they would have been used, providing a compelling insight into the lives of these craftspeople and warriors from our distant past.</p>
<p>Anthony Crutch, Museum Enabler at Birmingham Museum and Art Gallery</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Museum of Lancashire</title>
		<link>./../../../museum-of-lancashire/index.html</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2015 17:36:24 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[bm-editor]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Partner Stories]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=332</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[&#8220;&#8230;a unique opportunity for the Museum of Lancashire to develop an exciting new relationship with]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<blockquote><p><strong>&#8220;&#8230;a unique opportunity for the Museum of Lancashire to develop an exciting new relationship with the local Sikh community.&#8221; </strong>&#8211; Kate Eggleston-Wirtz</p></blockquote>
<p>The Museum of Lancashire hosted the Sikh fortress turban, a spotlight loan from the British Museum, between November 2014 and February 2015. This offered a unique opportunity for the Museum of Lancashire to develop an exciting new relationship with the local Sikh community. I was brought in as an artist to facilitate creative work about place and identity with the community and as a creative consultant for the community gallery area of the display.</p>
<p><img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-100" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/Derby-Ladies-2-2000x1168.jpg" alt="Derby Ladies 2" width="2000" height="1168" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/Derby-Ladies-2-2000x1168.jpg 2000w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/Derby-Ladies-2-300x175.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 2000px) 100vw, 2000px" /></p>
<p>As a collective we focused on ‘home’ whereby people of diverse age groups created their own individual house. I was also invited to photograph two Nagar Kirtan events that took place in Preston. This work, and further consultation with the local Sikh community members culminated in constructing my own creative response, an interactive educational artwork about the Sikh religion using a dollhouse as a symbol of a Gurdwara (Sikh temple).</p>
<p>The artwork was displayed alongside the community’s artwork during the exhibition. It has been used in educational settings and proven to be an effective learning source. It will continue to be offered in the future to raise awareness about Sikhism. It was a privilege to work on this project.</p>
<p>Kate Eggleston-Wirtz, freelance artist</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Russell-Cotes Art Gallery &#038; Museum, Bournemouth</title>
		<link>./../../../russell-cotes-art-gallery-museum-bournemouth/index.html</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2015 17:28:14 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[bm-editor]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Partner Stories]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=344</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[&#8220;All who witnessed the families enjoying their day or the chrysanthemum flowers floating down the]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<blockquote><p><strong>&#8220;All who witnessed the families enjoying their day or the chrysanthemum flowers floating down the stream and out to sea felt that they had been part of something very special.&#8221;</strong> &#8211; Sarah Newman</p></blockquote>
<p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-345" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/12138520_691213427680739_2954172969830595920_o-1.jpg" alt="Celebrating Ganesha, Russel-Cotes Museum and Art Gallery" width="1021" height="679" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/12138520_691213427680739_2954172969830595920_o-1.jpg 1021w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/12138520_691213427680739_2954172969830595920_o-1-300x200.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 1021px) 100vw, 1021px" /></p>
<p>On the most perfect September day, about 50 people descended along the cliff top from the Russell-Cotes Art Gallery &amp; Museum to the Bourne River in Lower Gardens. The group were there to immerse individual Ganesha statues in the water as the culmination of the Bournemouth Ganesha Festival, inspired by a 13<sup>th</sup> century sculpture of the Hindu Deity Ganesha, loaned by the British Museum as part of its touring exhibition <em>Celebrating Ganesha.</em></p>
<p>Witty, wise and famous as the placer and remover of obstacles, Ganesha is celebrated every year with a festival, <em>Ganeshchaturthi</em>, held in the month of Bhadrapada (August – September).</p>
<p>The loan was the springboard for the newly formed Dorset Indian Association (DIA) to work with the Russell-Cotes to choose Hindu objects from the collection for display, culminating in a day of worship, picnics on the lawn, children’s activities and celebration.</p>
<p>Mrs Vrushali Harihar of DIA said, ‘We feel blessed that Ganesha has come to Bournemouth’.  All who witnessed the families enjoying their day or the chrysanthemum flowers floating down the stream and out to sea felt that they had been part of something very special.</p>
<p>Sarah Newman, Programme Officer at Russell-Cotes Art Gallery &amp; Museum</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
